Guide to the Brooks McNamara Papers MSS 162
Fales Library and Special Collections
Brooks McNamara Papers
1896-1997
1970-1997
Fales Library and Special Collections
McNamara, Brooks
MSS 162
36 Linear Feet in 30 boxes, 5 record cartons, 2 manuscript boxes, and 1 oversize flat box
4 Cassettes
14.1 Gigabytes in 3 DVD-Rs
19 film reels
1 sound track film reels
3 videoreels (1 inch)
7 sound tape reels
The Brooks McNamara Papers are comprised almost entirely of McNamara's subject files on the expansive breadth of theater, drama, and performance in early American, early British, and contemporary American life. Materials include articles, brochures, catalogues, correspondence, drafts, magazines, manuscripts, newsletters, newspaper clippings, pamphlets, photocopies, photographs, postcards, posters, programs, student projects slides, audiocassettes, 8mm film, reel to reel video, reel to reel audio, and DVD-Rs.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was transferred from the Free Library of Philadelphia and donated by Brooks McNamara in 2005; additional materials were donated in 2009. The accession numbers associated with this collection are 2005.162 and 2009.162.
Arrangement
Materias are arranged in six series:
Series I: Subject Files
Series II: Printed Materials
Series III: Talks, Papers
Series IV: Anthologies [source materials]
Series V: Plays, written with Laurence Senelick
Series VI: Course Materials and Student Papers
Biographical / Historical
Brooks McNamara began teaching at NYU's Graduate Drama Department in 1968, and was instrumental in its transformation into the Performance Studies Department, which officially was started in 1980. He founded the Shubert Archives in 1976 and served as its Director for 20 years. McNamara's research, writing, and curatorial pursuits resulted in numerous publications, exhibitions, productions, and archival collections. His life work spanned the fields of theatre history, popular entertainments, public celebrations, and New York performance history. After retiring in 1996, McNamara remained Professor Emeritus of Performance Studies and Director Emeritus of the Shubert Archive. He died in May 2009.
List of Selected Publications:
Books:
The New York Concert Saloon: the Devil's Own Nights. Cambridge, U.K.; New York: Cambridge University Press, 2002.
Gower Champion Dance and American Musical Theatre. With David Payne-Carter and Stephen Nelson. Westport, Conn.: Greenwood Press, 1999.
Day of Jubilee: The Great Age Of Public Celebrations In New York, 1788-1909: Illustrated From The Collections Of The Museum Of The City Of New York. New Brunswick, N.J.: Rutgers University Press, 1997.
Inside the Minstrel Mask: Readings In Nineteenth-Century Blackface Minstrelsy. Edited with Annemarie Bean and James V. Hatch. Hanover, NH: Wesleyan University Press, 1996.
The Merry Muldoons and the Brighteyes Affair. New York: Orchard Books, 1992.
The Shuberts of Broadway: A History Drawn From The Collections Of The Shubert Archive. With the Shubert Archive. New York: Oxford University Press, 1990.
Edwin Booth's Legacy: Treasures From The Hampden-Booth Theatre Collection At The Players. Selected and organized by Raymond Wemmlinger and Brooks McNamara; catalogue by Raymond Wemmlinger and Brooks McNamara; with contributions by Robert A. Carter, José Ferrer and Paul Myers. [New York]: Hampden-Booth Theatre Library, 1989.
Plays from The Contemporary American Theater. New York: New American Library, 1988.
The Drama Review: Thirty Years of Commentary on The Avant-Garde. Edited by Brooks McNamara and Jill Dolan. Ann Arbor, Mich.: UMI Research Press, c1986.
American Popular Entertainments: Jokes, Monologues, Bits, and Sketches. [1st Ed.] New York City: Performing Arts Journal Publications, 1983.
Step right up. [1st ed.] Garden City, N.Y., Doubleday, 1976.
Theatres, Spaces, Environments: Eighteen Projects. Co-authored with Jerry Rojo and Richard Schechner. New York: Drama Book Specialists, 1975.
The American Playhouse in the Eighteenth Century. Cambridge, Mass.: Harvard University Press, 1969.
Chapters in Books:
"'For laughing purposes only': the literature of American popular entertainment." The American Stage: Social and Economic Issues from the Colonial Period to the Present. [Eds.] Ron Engle and Tice L. Miller. Cambridge [England]; New York: Cambridge University Press, 1993.
"'Something glorius': Greenwich Village and the theater." Greenwich Village: Culture and Counterculture. [Eds.] Rick Beard and Leslie Berlowitz, with the Museum of the City of New York. New Brunswick, N.J.: Published for the Museum of the City of New York by Rutgers University Press, 1993.
"The entertainment district at the end of the 1930s." Inventing Times Square: Commerce And Culture at the Crossroads of the World. William Robert Taylor. New York: Russell Sage Foundation, 1991.
Articles:
"Broadway: A Theatre Historian's Perspective." TDR, Vol. 45, No. 4 (Winter, 2001), pp. 125-128.
"Michael Kirby: 1931-1997." Richard Schechner; Brooks McNamara. TDR, Vol. 41, No. 3 (Autumn, 1997), pp. 5-8.
"Talking." The Drama Review: TDR, Vol. 31, No. 2 (Summer, 1987), pp. 39-56.
"Processional Performance: An Introduction." Barbara Kirshenblatt-Gimblett; Brooks McNamara. The Drama Review: TDR, Vol. 29, No. 3, Processional Performance (Autumn, 1985), pp. 2-5.
"The Medicine Show Log: Reconstructing a Traditional American Entertainment." The Drama Review: TDR, Vol. 28, No. 3, Reconstruction (Autumn, 1984), pp. 74-97.
"TDR: Memoirs of the Mouthpiece, 1955-1983." The Drama Review: TDR, Vol. 27, No. 4, Anniversary Issue: Dreams, Proposals, Manifestos (Winter, 1983), pp. 3-21.
"Stuart Sherman's Third Spectacle." The Drama Review: TDR, Vol. 20, No. 2, American Theatre Issue (Jun., 1976), pp. 47-55.
"An Interview with Percy Press and a Portfolio of Buskers." Percy Press; Brooks McNamara. Educational Theatre Journal, Vol. 27, No. 3, Popular Theatre (Oct., 1975), pp. 313-322.
"'A Congress of Wonders,' the Rise and Fall of the Dime Museum.' Emerson Society Quarterly, 20:3 (1974), 201-261.
"Popular Entertainments Issue: An Introduction." The Drama Review: TDR, Vol. 18, No. 1, Popular Entertainments (Mar., 1974), pp. 3-4.
"Scenography of Popular Entertainment." The Drama Review: TDR, Vol. 18, No. 1, Popular Entertainments (Mar., 1974), pp. 16-24.
"Spartakiade." John E. Bonn; Nathaniel Buchwald; Brooks McNamara; Mady Schuman. The Drama Review: TDR, Vol. 17, No. 4, International Festival Issue (Dec., 1973), pp. 99-112.
"Vessel: The Scenography of Meredith Monk. An Interview." Brooks McNamara; Meredith Monk. The Drama Review: TDR, Vol. 16, No. 1 (Mar., 1972), pp. 87-103.
"The Indian Medicine Show." Educational Theatre Journal, Vol. 23, No. 4 (Dec., 1971), pp. 431-445.
"Paterson Strike Pageant." Brooks McNamara; Jessie Ashley; F. Sumner Boyd; Mabel Dodge; William D. Haywood; John Reed; Margaret H. Sanger. The Drama Review: TDR, Vol. 15, No. 3 (Summer, 1971), pp. 60-71.
"Scene Design: 1876-1965 Ibsen, Chekhov, Strindberg." The Drama Review: TDR, Vol. 13, No. 2, Naturalism Revisited (Winter, 1968), pp. 77-91.
"Group III: Developing and Improving Artistic Leadership." Educational Theatre Journal, Vol. 20, No. 2, International Conference on Theatre Education and Development (Aug., 1968), pp. 291-297.
"David Douglass and the Beginnings of American Theater Architecture." Winterthur Portfolio, Vol. 3 (1967), pp. 112-135.
"The Stratford Jubilee: Dram to Garrick's Vanity." Educational Theatre Journal, Vol. 14, No. 2 (May, 1962), pp. 135-140.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact fales.library@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies. To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Related Materials
The Mark Hall Amitin/ World of Culture for the Performing Arts, Inc. Archive, MSS 121
The Richard Foreman Papers, MSS 152
The Jack Gelber Papers, MSS 146
The Arthur Kopit Papers, MSS 141
The Mabou Mines Archive, MSS 133
Scope and Contents
The Brooks McNamara Papers reflect McNamara's life work as a scholar and professor at NYU. The collection is comprised almost entirely of McNamara's subject files on the expansive breadth of theater, drama, and performance in early American, early British, and contemporary American life.
Organized in one main series of McNamara's subject files, as well as five smaller series which document his scholarly and creative writing, the collection features prominent sections of resources on Broadway, Circuses, Environmental Performance, Fairs and Festivals, Medicine Shows, Minstrelsy, Street Entertainments, Theatre and Theatres, and Vaudeville, as well as McNamara's own work as a scholar. One is able to trace the early development of Performance Studies as a discipline through McNamara's framing of "Popular Entertainments": performance and theatre on the stage, in the street, and in everyday life.
Collection materials consist of articles, brochures, catalogues, correspondence, drafts, magazines, manuscripts, newsletters, newspaper clippings, pamphlets, photocopies, photographs, postcards, posters, programs, student projects slides, audiocassettes, 8mm film, reel to reel video, reel to reel audio, and DVD-Rs.
The general date range for the collection spans the early-1970s to the mid-1990s, as this is when McNamara was actively collecting these materials. However, there are also historical pamphlets and booklets dating from the turn of the century through the 1960s.
Circus.; American drama (Comedy).; English drama -- 20th century.; Dime museums -- United States -- History.; Parades.; Pageants.; American drama -- 20th century.; New York (N.Y.) -- Social life and customs.; Melodrama.; Medicine shows -- History.; Monologues.; Minstrel shows -- United States -- History.; Fairs.; Experimental theater.; Film.; Festivals.; Theater -- Great Britain.; Street entertainers.; Popular culture -- United States.; Wit and humor.; Vaudeville -- United States.; Theaters -- United States.; Theater -- United States -- History -- 20th century.; Hatch-Billops Collection, Inc; Hatch, James V. (James Vernon), 1928-; Shubert Archive; Senelick, Laurence; Radio City Music Hall (New York, N.Y.)
- Series I: Subject Files, 69684
  Scope and Contents
  Series I contains contents articles, news clippings, programs, brochures, fliers, correspondence, photographs, postcards, student work, course materials, slides, audiocassettes, 8mm film, reel to reel video, reel to reel audio, and DVD-Rs from his time as a professor in NYU's Performance Studies Department. McNamara used his own subject headings to organize his scholarly research on popular entertainments, and they indicate his framing of performance both historically and in its prominent role in everyday life.
  Arrangement
  Series I is organized alphabetically according to McNamara's own subject headings. All folder titles that were not in McNamara's original index are marked in brackets. Most often the folders are listed as undated because the materials were either collected from a wide range of years, or they do not have dates on them at all. Due to the large number of items in each folder, contents are not listed in detail, but rather by material type. In rare cases, an item of note is described. Materials in the 2009 accretion, boxes 36-38, were added to the end of Series I; original order and folder titles were retained.
  - Index to P.E. Files: List of folder titles/categories; BM notes on 5x7 index cards listing partial contents of individual folders; List of audio cassettes., undated; 70222 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General
    Offsite Barcode: 31142042233703
  - Actors I: Articles on 19th century actors/acting; oral history [?] of Lotta Evelyn Parker Haesloop – includes photos., undated; 70221 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Actors II: List of theater interviews since 1990 by the Oral History Library of the American Jewish Committee; various articles/images on (mainly) 19th century actors/acting; entries on American Performance Art and individual artists by Angelika Festa for Cambridge Guide to American Theater (1992)., undated; 70220 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Actors III: Articles, photos, brochures, newspaper and magazine clippings; 8x10 photos of George White's Scandals actresses from the 1920s; dissertation proposal on Carmen Miranda by Zeca Ligiero [1996]., undated; 70219 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Actors [news clippings], undated; 70218 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Actors' Social Status (chapters 1-4): 4 chapters of computer printout [possibly for BM book, mid-1980s], 70217 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - African: performance/event announcements, pamphlets, programs; BM notes; student paper on New Wave Black Dance; newspaper and scholarly articles on Black performance; bibliographies., undated; 70216 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Amateur Theatre [Part I]: articles/book chapters., undated; 70215 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Amateur Theatre [Part II]: articles/book chapters., undated; 70214 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Amateur Theatre [Part III]: articles/book chapters., undated; 70213 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Amateur Theatre [Part IV]: articles/book chapters., undated; 70212 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Amateur Theatre (Mostly American) [Part V]: articles/book chapters., undated; 70211 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Amateur Theatre (Mostly American) [Part VI]: articles/book chapters., undated; 70210 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Amateur Theatre (Mostly American) [Part VII]: articles/book chapters., undated; 70209 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Amateur Theatre (Mostly American) [Part VIII]: articles/book chapters., undated; 70208 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Amateur Theatre [Part IX]: clippings, various amateur performances – Hasty Pudding programs, 1983-84., undated; 70207 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - American Theatre I: Course materials for NYU course on American Theatre, student papers; list of American theatre companies; BM entry on American Theater for Dictionary of American History; selected bibliography on American Theater "Beginnings to 1900"., undated; 70206 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - American Theatre Wing: correspondence., 1992; 70205 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Amusement Business - Anniversary Issue: 75th Anniversary issue of Amusement Business magazine., 1969; 70204 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Amusement Parks I: Clippings, photocopies, brochures about U.S. and British parks; typescript BM article on Palisades Park (1971)., 1969-1976; 70203 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Offsite Barcode: 31142042233711
  - Amusement Parks II: Clippings, photocopies, brochures; selected bibliography of English seaside entertainments; student bibliography of pleasure gardens, amusement parks and piers (1972); Theatre Crafts magazine theme parks issue (9/72) containing BM article; programs from the Apollo Theatre, Atlantic City (1930s)., undated; 70202 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Amusement Parks III: Clippings, photocopies, brochures; student paper on Turkish Coffeehouses, Picnic Grounds and Pleasure Gardens; excerpt from student paper (?) on Dreamland (Coney Island) show "Fighting the Flames"., undated; 70201 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Amusement Parks IV: Clippings, photocopies, brochures; excerpts of student papers, qualifying exams and bibliographies., undated; 70200 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Amusement Parks V: Clippings, photocopies, brochures; excerpts of student papers, qualifying exams and bibliographies., undated; 70199 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Amusement Parks VI: Clippings, photocopies, brochures., undated; 70198 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Amusement Parks VII: Clippings, photocopies, brochures; snapshots of unidentified S.S. park; no student work., undated; 70197 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Amusement Parks VIII [misc.]: Clippings, photocopies, articles., undated; 70196 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Animals: Clippings, programs, brochures; postcards and letters to BM from Mae Noell of Noell's Ark Chimpanzee Farm, Tarpon Springs, FL (1973); Ricky Jay note to BM and copy of "Jay's Journal of Anomalies" (1994); photocopy and article on dancing dogs of Sadlers Wells (late 18th C.), undated; 70195 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Art Deco Society: Correspondence., 1994; 70194 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Asian, undated; 70193 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Asian, undated; 70192 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Asian [Chinese Theatres in America - Part I], undated; 70191 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Asian [Chinese Theatres in America - Part II], undated; 70190 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Asian Performance [Arts of Chinatown NY], undated; 70189 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Asian [Four Seas], undated; 70188 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Asian [Pan Asian/Chinese], undated; 70187 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Asian Performance: Syllabi for 2 courses [not BM] on Orientalism., undated; 70186 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Asian Theatre and Society: Dissertation, "Theatre in Modernizing Societies: A Survey of Some Aspects of Modern Asian Theatre Developments" (1971); booklet, "A People's Theatre for Community Development in Tamilnadu" (1987)., undated; 70185 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Automata: Clippings., undated; 70184 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Avant - Garde: Articles on Tadeuz Kantor and Dario Fo; student bibliography on experimental performance space, 1960s-1980s., 1986-1991.; 70183 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Bibliography: Bookseller catalogs and info; student reading lists., undated; 70182 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    Offsite Barcode: 31142042233729
  - [Broadway - misc.]: Articles, clippings; BM talk on Times Square District in 1930s., undated; 70181 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - [Bucks County Historical Society], undated; 70180 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Burlesque I: Clippings; student work; BM notes; interview (undated) with Charles "Mac" McJinney (b.1885)., 70179 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Burlesque II: Student papers., undated; 70178 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Burlesque III: Clippings, articles; photocopy of "Strip Tease: the Vanished Art of Burlesque," by H.M. Alexander (1938)., undated; 70177 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Burlesque IV: Playbills for "Grind", "Honky Tonk Nights", and "Sugar Babies"; journal articles; script for musical – "Scandals in Heaven" by Joseph Lesser and Mark Barkan (1987-8); clippings about Lydia Thompson., undated; 70176 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Burlesque V: Clippings, articles; photos - Lydia Thompson, Lillian Elmore and Nat Goodwin; program (1989) from Joey Faye Burlesque show., undated; 70175 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Cabaret: Brochures for Parisian floor shows., undated; 70174 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Carnival I: Clippings, postcards, photographs, photocopies, articles, pamphlets., undated; 70173 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Carnival II: Clippings, photocopies, articles., undated; 70172 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Carnival III: Clippings, photocopies, articles; information regarding an exhibition on the social history of the country fair at Chemung County Historical Society., undated; 70171 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Carnival IV: Clippings, postcards, photographs, photocopies, articles, pamphlets., undated; 70170 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Carnival V: Clippings, photocopies, articles; student papers; article by BM., undated; 70169 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Carnivals, Circuses [misc.]: Clippings, photocopies, articles, pamphlets., undated; 70168 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Carousel: Clippings, articles, photocopies., undated; 70167 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Celebrations: 1996 Olympics; Waitangi Day (New Zealand); Feast of St. Francis (1991)., undated; 70166 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Censorship: NYPL LC exhibition pamphlet; partial bibliography., undated; 70165 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Chautauqua I: Clippings, pamphlets, articles, correspondence., undated; 70164 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Chautauqua II: Clippings, pamphlets, articles., undated; 70163 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Chautauqua III: Clippings, articles, student papers, bibliographies., undated; 70162 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Cheap Theater and Penny Gaff: hand-written notes; photocopies., undated; 70161 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Chorus Girls: Postcard for musicals exhibition; postcard for documentary on Ziegfeld., undated; 70160 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    Offsite Barcode: 31142042233737
  - Circle Stock: Manuscript on circle stock., undated; 70159 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Circus I: Photocopies, clippings, articles., undated; 70158 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Circus II: Article, student paper., undated; 70157 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Circus III: Postcards, pamphlets, articles, clippings., undated; 70156 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Circus IV: Ringling Bros Route Book (1964); articles, photocopies., undated; 70155 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Circus V: Pamphlets, correspondence, articles, notes, photocopies, clippings, photographs., undated; 70154 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Circus VI: Pamphlets, correspondence, articles, notes, photocopies, clippings, photographs., undated; 70153 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Circus VII: Proposal for The New York School for Clown and Circus Arts; photocopied catalogue of circus art., undated; 70152 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Circus VIII: Articles; interview; BM Circus paper., undated; 70151 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Circus IX: Clippings., undated; 70150 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Circus X: Clippings, pamphlets, postcards, photocopies, articles, photographs and negatives., undated; 70149 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Circus XI: Clippings, articles, postcards, correspondence, student papers., undated; 70148 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Circus XII: Clippings, pamphlets, postcards, articles, photographs., undated; 70147 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Circus XIII: Clippings, articles, correspondence, student work; Ringling Museums brochure; list of NY State Museum's Circus Poster Collection., undated; 70146 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Circus XIV: Clippings, articles, course materials, research materials., undated; 70145 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Circus XV: Clippings, pamphlets, postcards, articles, photocopies, photographs., undated; 70144 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Circus XVI: Manuscript copy of "Step Right Up: the Adventure of Circus in America," by Hoh and Rough., undated; 70143 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - [Citizen Kane]: Articles., undated; 70142 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Civic Pageantry I: Clippings, articles, programs, pamphlets., undated; 70141 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Civic Pageantry II: Student paper., undated; 70140 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Civic Pageantry III: Articles, student papers., undated; 70139 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Civic Pageantry IV: Clippings, articles, pamphlets, photocopies, postcards, student papers., undated; 70138 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Clowns I: Clippings, articles, programs., undated; 70137 (Box 5, Folder 86)
    Offsite Barcode: 31142042233745
  - Clowns II: Articles., undated; 70136 (Box 5, Folder 87)
  - Clowns III: Clippings, articles, programs, correspondence., undated; 70135 (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - Clowns IV: Manuscripts., undated; 70134 (Box 5, Folder 89)
  - Clubs, Fraternities, Lodges: Clippings, pamphlets., undated; 70133 (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - Clubs II: Clippings, articles, photocopies, pamphlets., undated; 70132 (Box 5, Folder 91)
  - Comedy I: Articles, photocopies., undated; 70131 (Box 5, Folder 92)
  - Comedy II: Clippings, articles, photocopies, bibliography., undated; 70130 (Box 5, Folder 93)